<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on d.kens</title>
    <link>https://dkensinger.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on d.kens</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 11:17:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dkensinger.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programming Languages I know</title>
      <link>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/programming-languages-i-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 11:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/programming-languages-i-know/</guid>
      <description>Here is an annotated list of the programming languages I know (or have used). Listed in the order I first used them:&#xA;MS BASIC ran on my first computer, an IBM PC with an 8088 processor (1981?) used to copy programs from computer magazines first learned the concept of subroutines with GOSUB command PASCAL my first formal computer course used this language had to share a central compiler at school had to take turns on a limited set of terminals don&amp;rsquo;t think I ever got an entire program to run correctly (as intended) hated the whole experience!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Just a Hobby</title>
      <link>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/just-a-hobby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 15:24:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/just-a-hobby/</guid>
      <description>(original article written in December 2016)&#xA;The Start Programming. It’s my new hobby. Well, also reading about programming. Hacker News, Reddit, all kinds of blogs and other sites. Also computer science. Also a hobby. Algorithms, big O notation, functional versus imperative languages, searching, sorting, data structures, strong versus weak typed languages, operator overloading, etc. Ad infinitum. I think it’s fascinating. Not terribly fun sometimes, not easy to grasp most of the time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Download data from the web</title>
      <link>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/download-data-from-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 19:16:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/download-data-from-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Task A colleague of mine has been entering meta-data for books through a web-based portal (let&amp;rsquo;s call it site A) over the last several years. Earlier this year we found out we needed to transfer a great deal of that data from the website to another place (site B). Unfortunately, even though there was a way to export a summary of all the entries which contained much of the information, there were several important pieces missing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fizz-Buzz: deluxe edition</title>
      <link>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/fizz-buzz-deluxe-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2017 23:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dkensinger.github.io/blog/fizz-buzz-deluxe-edition/</guid>
      <description>Origin story I remember a game I played in school called “Fizz Buzz” where we sat in a circle and progressed around the circle by counting up from “one”. The rule was: replace the number with “Fizz” if it was a multiple of 5, “Buzz” if it was a multiple of 7 and “FizzBuzz” if it was a multiple of both 5 and 7. There may have been some direction changes (and possibly drinking) involved but I can’t recall.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
